Association for Research and Enlightenment Collection
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
- Publications, 1931 2015
  - Box 6
    - A.R.E. News, 1981; Folder 6:9; Brittell, Katherine A.; Boyle, Richard; January, 1981 -ARE Celebrates 50th Anniversary: A Look at its Beginnings -Join Network of Prayer Groups Circling Globe (Mark Thurston) -extracts from readings in July 1929 and March 1931 -Business Conferees Share Insights (Lauren Luedeman, Business Conferee) -Search for God Group of the Month: Members of the United Nations -Over the Wall: All Points Bulletin from Judith Stevens -Temple Beautiful Experience...An Interview with Bill and Fonchen Lord -New Study Groups -1981 Wilderness Retreats -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -February Field Programs -Join Us in Meditation February, 1981 -Audio Visual: An Interview with Jeff Sherwood -ARE Clinic Breaks Ground on Healing Center and Spiritual Community... -quotations from Creative Force Circulating File -Cayce Teachings Used in Business (John Levin, Ledger-Star Staff Writer) -March Field Programs -Special Gift to Study Group Members -New Study Groups -Researcher Needs Books (Carolyn Di Paolo) -ASFG Group of the Month (Hollywood No. 2, California) -50 Years Ago in February... (excerpts from lecture by Edgar Cayce) -Over the Wall (Lucille G. Stewart, Pasadena, California) -Congress Update by 1981 Congress Committee -Youth Retreat: The Next Step for Young People -Remember Camp and Plan Ahead (Mary Nowak, Youth Activities Coordinator) -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -Membership Tradition Dates from Time of Edgar Cayce (Robert O. Clapp, Manager, Individual Services Department) -Join Us in Meditation March, 1981 -Welcome to Headquarters! 1981 Summer Conference Season (Marianna Theo, Headquarters Programming Coordinator) -Teams, Councils, and Regional Representatives Coordinator Selected (Lyn Costaldo) -50 Years Ago in March...(excerpt from What I Believe lecture by Edgar Cayce) -Field Volunteers Support ARE Headquarters (Lyn Costaldo) -Regional Representatives Serve Members (Lyn Costaldo) -Changes and Additions: 1981 Conference Schedule -ARE Headquarters Spring Retreats -ARE Camp Opens 1981 Season -New Family Week Added to Camp Program -Tuition Assistance Available -Teaching in Any Age (Mary Nowak) -quotations from Man in the Earth Circulating File -April Field Programs -Over the Wall (Frank Schultz) -New Study Groups -Loving Indifference -Search for God Group of the Month (Fountain Valley No. 1, California, Virginia Jenkins) -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -Congress Update (Judy Carrino, 1981 Vice-Chairman) -Join Us in Meditation April, 1981 -A Search for God Starts in Church (Margaret Marshik) -Over 700 Respond to Programming Request (Marianna Theo) -Think on These Things (reading 262-64) -Come to the Beach in May! (Marianna Theo) -Over the Wall (Judith Stevens) -Help Shorten Library Waiting List -50 Years Ago in April... (reading 254-55) -Multiplying Riches: A Dream Message (Robert Krajenke) -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, January 9-10, 1981 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -Information on Latest Circulating Files -Five Commentaries by the ARE Clinic Added to Files -Magic in the Mountains (Judith Stevens) -Congress Update (Betty Guzynski, 1981 Congress Secretary) -Children Can Share Activities While Parents Attend Conference -Notes From... Nancy Stephenson, Program Manager -New Study Groups -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -May Field Programs -Join Us in Meditation May, 1981 -Vision Quest for America: Celebrate July 4th with ARE -Egypt is First Choice -A Life of Service, A Life of Prayer - Ruth LeNoir (obituary) -Join Us in Meditation -The Summer of 1979 B.C. (Missy Boyd) -What's New in Audio-Visual (Jeff Sherwood) -What Is a Prison Sponsor? -Over the Wall: Follow-up on Request to Members (Judith Stevens) -Experiment with a Jet Lag Remedy -Search for God (Mobile No. 2 and No. 3, Alabama) -Newly Appointed Regional Representatives -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole, Amanda Wakester) -50 Years Ago in May...(Edgar Cayce letters from the spring of 1931) -Plans, Proper Procedure and a Promise for 1981 Congress (Fred Kolb, Congress Chairman) -Memo to All Teams People, Council Leaders, Regional Representatives, and Interested Members (Lyn Costaldo) -Come to the Beach in June! (Marianna Theo) -Cooperating Doctors List Grows and Changes Name (Sandra Duggan, R.N., Supervisor of ARE Therapy Department) -Summer Field Programs -Brief Notes June, 1981 -Critics Acclaim The Freak (Jeffrey A. Frank, Staff Writer, The Washington Star, etc.) -Search for God Group of the Month: United Nations Update -Could I Profit More in Another Field? (Steven Edsey) -Join Us in Meditation -50 Years Ago in June... -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, March 20-21, 1981 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -Library Plans Necessary Expansion (Stephen Jordan, Library Manager) -First Annual Child Development Symposium (Robert Witt) -Over the Wall: A Long Day -Come to the Beach in July! (Marianna Theo) -Readings Research Needs Your Help -New Study Groups -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -Prayer Services Update -Join Congress at Home July, 1981 -Blessed Are the Peacemakers (Thomas Banyacya) -Prescription for Profit: Fifth Annual ARE Business Conference (Cheryl Salerno, Editorial Department) -Hopi Leader Is Guest at Youth Conference (Mary Burke Nowak) -Atlantis Collection Made More Available (Charlotte Schoen) -Search for God Group of the Month (Vienna Study Group No. 2, Virginia) -A Positive Word from Boston... (Arlene Bacon, Corresponding Secretary for the Greater Boston Search for God Council) -Travel to Ancient Civilizations -New Study Groups -Hawaii Tour -Come to the Beach in August! -Special Weekend Programs Unlocking the Treasure: Circulating File, Be a Channel of Blessings (Mae St. Clair) -50 Years Ago in July... -Over the Wall: Cayces Held in Jail Cell -S.O.S.: sponsor needed in the Jackson, Louisiana area for prison Study Group -Happy Trio Helps Three States (Tanya Wood, Ann Jaffin, Esther Ham; Lyn Costaldo, Regional Representatives Coordinator) -What God Can Do: The Hand of the Master (Theresa Cole) -Join Us in Meditation August, 1981 -Patterns for Holistic Health: An Interview with Dee Shambaugh (Miriam Kent, Assistant Field Program Coordinator) -Explore the Wilds: ARE Wilderness Retreats -Come to the Beach in September! (Marianna Theo) -Special Weekend Program: The Revelation with J. Everett Irion -Fall Field Programs -50 Years Ago in August... -50th Anniversary Celebration (Lorraine Pitcher, Communications Department) -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, September 25-26, 1981 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -Members and Friends Need Regional Reps (Lynn Costaldo) -Invite Sharing of Dream Adventures (Mary Nowak, Youth Activities Coordinator) -Topics of Two New Circulating Files (Robert O. Clapp) -Study Group of the Month: Creativity Flourishes in Louisville Seven -Home Research Project: Meditation, Dreams and You -What God Can Do: Tensions Melt Away (Theresa Cole) -Over the Wall: Special Cargo (Judith Stevens) -New Study Groups -Join Us in Meditation September, 1981 -Therapy Department Grows as It Heals (Robert Clapp) -Have You Heard? -50 Years Ago in September... -A Catholic, a Jew, and a Protestant Review First Study Group Lessons -Study Group of the Month: Growth Opens the Door to Greater Love (Arlington Heights No. 2, Illinois) -New Study Groups -A Visit to the ARE Therapy Department (with photographs) -Renowned Psychics Discuss Abilities (Miriam Kent) -Copper Crafter with a Heart of Gold (Anthony Mocciolo obituary) -Join Us in Meditation -October Field Programs -Over the Wall: Inmate Finds Freedom in God (Adrian Ashcraft) -Psychologist Finds Cayce Readings Aid Psychotherapy (Richard Tamura, Psychologist, Deerfield Correctional Center) October, 1981 -Office of Development to Make Long-Range Plans a Reality (Lee Samaroff, Executive Secretary, Office of Development) -Meet Our Congress Chairwoman (Helen Ruth Schroeder) -50 Years Ago in October... -Prayer Services Continues to Expand -What God Can Do: Unseen Hands at Work (Theresa Cole) -Join Us in Meditation -A Kaleidoscopic Review of the 1981 Congress -The Purpose of Development -Over the Wall: Freedom Is a Spiritual State -November Field Programs -Study Group of the Month: San Diego No. 10 -Library Seeks to Expand Areas of Psychical Research / Metaphysics (Stephen Jordan) -Readings Research Needs Your Experience (Stuart Dean, Readings Research Department) -New Study Groups November, 1981 -The Remnant Author Enchants ARE Audiences (Mary LaCroix) -E.C.F. Recipient of Faith Howell Estate -50 Years Ago in November... -What's News in Audio-Visual (Jeff Sherwood) -Study Group of the Month: Treats for Elderly South Africans -New Study Groups -The Birth of the Remnant (Mary LaCroix) -ARE Clinic Symposia -Celebrate Christmas As a Member of ARE Family -Over the Wall: An Open Letter to ARE (Linn Jacobs) -Join Us in Meditation December, 1981 A Christmas Message (Theresa Cole) -Join Us in Meditation -50 Years Ago in December... -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, September 25-26, 1981 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -Cayce Readings Aid Board Member to Found Holistic Center (Dawn Ahart) -A Miracle Can Happen in California: Earthquake Threat Mobilizes Spirit of Cooperation, An ARE Interview with Judith Skutch -Questions to Ponder from Hugh Lynn Cayce's Earth Changes Update -Unlocking the Treasure: The Quotes and Similes Series, Circulating File: First Things First -Summer Reflections (Judith Stevens, Mary Nowak) -Over the Wall: Indirect Gift Benefits Many -January Field Programs -All Pledges Received for Library / Conference Center -Study Group of the Month: A Joyful Debt (Robert Jasper, Field Study Group Organizer -New Study Groups -Seasons Greetings from the ARE Staff
    - A.R.E. News, 1982; Folder 6:10; Brittell, Katherine A.; Boyle, Richard; Redman, Velva A.; January, 1982 -50th Anniversary of Congress (Lyn Costaldo) -Director Chosen for Office of Development (Glenn Sanderfur) -Unlocking the Treasure: The Quotes and Similes Series, Circulating File: First Find Self -Introducing Mr. Ojo Ajayi -New Library Policies for Borrowers by Mail (Stephen Jordan) -Join Us in Meditation: Know Thyself -New Study Groups -Set Your Sails for the Virgin Islands -Vorbereitung Auf Das Leben Im Neuen Zeitalter - Deutsche Konferenz (Linda M. Betts, Study Group Department) -Group of the Month: A Personal Experience: The Power of Prayer Applied (Jim Dixon, Dallas No. 3, Texas) -Over the Wall: Prison Became His Teacher -A New Year's Gift from ARE to Members -Twenty-Two City TV Conference Presents ARE Speakers (Norman Shealy, Harmon Bro, Gladys McGarey) -A Conference Experience (Sophie Freeman) -February Field Programs -What God Can Do: For His Is the Joyous Life (Theresa Cole) -A Senior Citizen Finds ARE Makes Life Worth Living! (Alice W. Edminster) -Angel Points the Way for ARE Educators (Robert Witt) -Jesus and the Brooklyn Bridge (Elaine Retholtz) -Notice to Teachers February, 1982 -ARE Programming Department Begins Cooperative Efforts with Atlantic University -How to Become a Contributing Member -Co-Creators with God: The Latest Circulating File from The Quotes and Similes Series, compiled by Mae St. Clair -Getting the Most out of Your Membership (Robert O. Clapp) -1982 Wilderness Retreats -ARE Camp: Youth Activities -Office of Development (Lee Samaroff) -What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) -Over the Wall: Prison as a Creative Opportunity -March Field Programs -Join Us in Meditation: What Is My Ideal? -In Memoriam: Arthur Twitchell, President of the American Society for Psychical Research -New Study Groups March, 1982 -New Home Research Projects Enhance Membership Benefits -Elsie and Bill Sechrist Renew Vows on 50th Wedding Anniversary -Sound Nutrition and Other Notes of Interest: A Musical Interview with Steven Halpern -ARE Tour Schedule for 1982 -Join Us in Meditation: Know Thyself -Over the Wall -ARE Library Attracts Researchers (Edward R. Birchmore) -Jesus, the Essenes and the Second Coming: An Easter Retreat -Announcing a Special Study Group Project -The Study Group Readings: A Tool for Soul Growth (Judith Stevens) -April Field Programs -They Said It Couldn't Be Done (ARE Clinic, Arizona well) -1982 Congress Auction Items -Late Announcements Require Thoughtful Action April, 1982 -Bantam to Publish Book Based on Dr. Puryear's Covenant Series -Research Project in Your Monthly Mail -Release (Frederick Steinway) -Join Us in Meditation: Faith -Notices -Office of Development: Circle of Light -Study Group of the Month: Gail Daily Reports (Speedway No. 1, Indiana) -New Study Groups -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, January 22-23, 1982 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -The ARE Requests Your Board Nominee Suggestions (Charles Thomas Cayce) -Trustee Aided by His Cayce Reading: Bill Lord -A journey without distance to a goal that has never changed: An interview with Judith Skutch -Congress Update (Robert Hendrickson) -May / June Field Programs -Receive Credit at Field Instructors Seminar -May Headquarters Conferences -Interested in ARE Land Project? Questionnaire Now Available -ARE Now Recruiting Volunteers for Work-Scholarship Program May, 1982 -And the Winners Are...(Conference of Your Choice contest) -India Tour a Bridge Builder -Sai Baba's Comments Parallel Cayce Readings -Group of the Month: The Perfect Gift -Over the Wall: Wife of Former Prisoner Seeks Aid for Inmates -New Study Groups -The Conference Experience (Jade Carroll) -Vacation at Mingus Mountain Camp -ARE June Headquarters Conferences -Student Receives Credits for Research at ARE (Valorie Haslam) -Letter to the Editor, Re: Earthquakes (Grethe Tedrick) -Bring Your Child to a "Junior Conference" (Mary Burke, Youth Activities Coordinator) -In Memoriam: Richmond Seay -Why an Office of Development? (Glenn Sanderfur) -Congress Update (1982 Congress Committee) -Join Us in Meditation: Virtue and Understanding -In Everything Give Thanks: What God Can Do (Theresa Cole) June, 1982 -A Salute to Unsung Heroes and Heroines: ARE Volunteers -A Touch of History: 1982, The Second Wave (Cheryl Salerno, Editorial Department); (Robert O. Clapp, J. Everett Irion, Nell Clairmonte, Marjorie Bonney, Helen Love, Robert A. Adriance, Lester Babcoke, Grace Huffman) -Lydia J. Schrader Gray - A Celebrator of Life (obituary) -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, March 26-27, 1982 (Hugh Lynn Cayce) -Dimensions in Healing: New Approaches in Health Care -Over the Wall: ...Until My Husband Went to Jail) -A Thank You to Friends of ARE's Prison Program -Meditation Conference: An Inspiring Experience (Dan Gibbons) -ARE July Headquarters Conferences -What God Can Do: Answers to Prayer Put on Hold (Theresa Cole) -Volunteers Aid Prayer Services (Donna Abdennour, Prayer Services Secretary) -Join Us in Meditation: Fellowship -New Study Groups -Something Good For You! Field Volunteer Programs '82 -Group of the Month: A Trans-Pacific Hug (Melbourne No. 2, Australia) -Join a Wilderness Retreat July, 1982 -The Freak Reopens in New York City -His Own Country: Excerpts from a prize-winning essay in a literary contest at the Princess Anne County Fair, Virginia Beach, Va., Sept. 22, 1949, by Gladys Davis Turner -How Would You Describe ARE? -Why ARE Is Not a Cult (Herbert Puryear) -Motivating the Spirit in Business: Sixth Annual Business Conference -On A Search for God, Book III (Judith Stevens) -New Study Groups -Over the Wall: Choosing to Love and Listen -You Can Help -Circulating File Department Happily Snowed Under in Spite of the Season! -Search for the Center (Lee Samaroff) -Join Us in Meditation: Patience -Nurse / Homemaker Travels Path Set by Ten-Year Plan (Lyn Costaldo) -Field Instructor Training Seminars on Leadership -July Field Programs -More Tips on How to Overcome Jet Lag (Robert Dean Meredith) -August Headquarters Conferences August, 1982 -Education of the Young Important Aspect of New Age (Robert Witt) -Mysteries of the Mind: New Fall Course -Happy Rebirth-day, Ralph (Ralph Malcolm obituary) -Defining ARE -Expectations of ARE Regarding Contributions (Charles Thomas Cayce) -Book Drop Contributed to Library (Stephen Jordan) -Rolling Thunder Speaks: Excerpts from two 1982 Norfolk Va. newspaper articles -Fall Field Programs -New Regional Symposia Highlight Plans for Field Programs -Join Us in Meditation: The Open Door -Regional Representatives Serve Members (Lyn Costaldo) -What God Can Do: Kinship Through Prayer (Theresa Cole) -Group of the Month: Nominate Your Favorite Leader -New Study Groups -ARE September Headquarters Conferences September, 1982 -Nancy Wittmeier Replaces Sandy Duggan as Therapy Supervisor -Dr. Puryear's New Book Released by Bantam -Well Done, Good and Faithful Servant: Memorial Service for Hugh Lynn Cayce, March 16, 1907 - July 4, 1982 -Join Us in Meditation: In His Presence -To Participants in the Dreams and Meditation Research Project Autumn of 1981 -First Leadership Seminar a Big Success -Highlights from the Annual ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, June 4-5 (Charles Thomas Cayce) -A Sense of Oneness: A Report on the 1982 Congress -Visits to England and Africa (Bill Sechrist, International Representative -Field Programs: October -The Spirit is Getting Lighter (Puget Sound Council of Study Groups -Central Texas Retreat -New Study Groups -Vermont Wilderness Retreat -A Thank You to Lydia's Many Friends -ARE Land Expansion Project Put on Hold -Library Acquires New Books on the Psychology of Woman: A Gift from the William Wade Fund -Virginia Beach Conferences of Note October, 1982 -Dr. Gladys McGarey Elected AHMA President -New Board Member a Psychologist - Emphasizes Research (James C. Windsor, Ph.D.) -Excerpts from Dr. Gladys McGarey's AHMA Acceptance Speech -What God Can Do: Gain Strength Through Daily Prayer (Theresa Cole) -November Field Programs -New Position for Dr. Puryear with Well Spring -A Holistic Theory of Mental Illness (James C. Windsor, Ph.D.) -Group of the Month: A Flower in the Rockies (Golden No. 2, Colorado) -Announcing! 1983 New Year's Conference -Ten Years of Service: An Anniversary to Celebrate "Flight" (Judith Stevens) -A Tribute to Les Wilmore -How to Recognize a True Prophet: A Dream Report (Ricky Donovan Leonard -Letter to the Editor -Join Us in Meditation: The Cross and the Crown -New Study Groups November, 1982 -Susan Strasberg Speaks at New Year's Conference -In Everything Give Thanks -Sykes's Atlantis Collection Offers Challenging Ideas (Charlotte Schoen) -Member Finds Wonderment in Service (Lyn Costaldo, Edith Wilson) -The ARE Christmas Three -Skiing in Vermont -Over the Wall: Journey into the Whirlwind -Spirit is the Life, Mind the Builder, Physical the Result: A Circulating File from the Quotes and Similes Series, compiled by Mae Gimbert St. Clair -Love, Light and Laughter: Healing Powers of the New Age: 16th Annual ARE Clinic Symposium on Holistic Health -Tuition Refund Policy -Group of the Month: ARE Brisbane -1983 Congress: Service a Key Word (Jim Bloomquist, 1983 Congress Chairman) -What God Can Do: Brighten the Corner Where You Are (Theresa Cole) -November Field Programs -Join Us in Meditation: The Lord Thy God is One -New Study Groups December, 1982 -Archaeologist Discusses Sphinx Project (Mark Lehner) -Gift Sparks Videotape Program (Rudy and Georgean Barden) -Listen With Your Heart (Nancy S. Edwards) -Highlights from ARE Board of Trustees Meeting, October 1-3, 1982 (Charles Thomas Cayce) -ECF Supports ARCE Sphinx Project: An Interview with Mark Lehner -Study Group Together Fifteen Years (Dundalk No. 1, Maryland) -Join Us in Meditation: Love -Over the Wall: Be More Loving -Happy Holidays from the ARE Staff